CARLOS DE QUEIROZ

Software Engineer

carlosabqf@gmail.com

365 275 5429

in /in/carlosabqf

Parrie-ON, Canada

SUMMARY

Senior Software Engineer with *14 years of experience, with a degree in Telematics (BSc, 2007) and Computer Science (MSc, 2012). I'm always eager for challenges, to learn, and to share my knowledge. Extensive experience in different types of software projects, from building systems on traditional J2EE architectures, embedded systems, REST APIs, and Mobile applications. I Am enthusiastic about teamwork and agile and innovative methodologies. As a developer, I'm prepared and confident to identify and solve cross-cutting software development challenges related to object-oriented software system architectures or unconventional ones. I'm currently a Backend Java Engineer working for Taller at Paypal.

SKILLS

Languages: Java, JavaScript, C, SQL, XML, HTML, CSS.

Tech. and Frameworks: Java EE, JSF, EJB, Spring Boot, React, Android, AWS, Docker, JPA, JUnit

Tools and Principles: Maven, Docker, Weblogic, Jenkins, SCRUM, TDD, BDD, Linux, Design Patterns, Oracle

database, Primefaces, SOLID, Git and other VCS

WORK HISTORY

10/2022 - Actual Java API Engineer

Paypal

• I am developing and maintaining APIs in a microservice architecture.

Java / Spring Boot / TestNG / Wiremock / Postman / Docker / Scrum / JIRA

06/2021 - 10/2022 Senior Software Engineer

Dataprev

• I worked at the backend of a new National Single Registration System based on JAVA and Spring Boot. This new registration system and its national-wide social information database should be used in the process of granting social benefits.

Java / Spring Boot / Javascript / React / Cordova

02/2020 - 06/2021 Project Manager/Tech Leader

Dataprev

- I worked as a team leader helping with the use of the technologies and mapping the business necessities to practical activities (using Java, Spring Boot, and React). I also led the team (6-8 engineers) as a project manager handling the external clients, project schedule, and scope.
- Delivered two very large national-wide and important systems for the Brazilian government. The first one
 allowed citizens to prove their liveness using a mobile phone. This would ensure they could still receive the
 financial support they need from the government, overall, during the restrictions of the COVID-19 pandemic.
 The other one was a system, also based on Java, Spring Boot, and React, to provide an interface to daily
 activities of the public social service.

Java / Spring Boot / React / Scrum / Systems Design and Integration

04/2014 - 10/2022 Senior Software Engineer

Dataprev

- Dataprev is responsible for developing and maintaining systems for Brazilian social security. Dataprev processes 34.5 million pension payments and other benefits to Brazilian citizens and the total payments handled are equivalent to 5% of Brazil's GDP. The company keeps the most extensive database of social data in Latin America, storing data related to almost 200 million people.
- I helped in the development and maintenance of a task manager system that structured the process of every medical exam necessary to apply for a social security service.
- I worked on developing and maintaining a task manager system that optimizes the process for grant pensions, and other benefits and provides services to Brazilian citizens through multiple channels. That system is being used in 3500+ Social Security agencies across Brazil.
- I worked developing and maintaining a social care scheduling management system (capable of handling 100,000+ appointments per hour).

Java / Java EE / Spring Boot / React / JUnit / SQL and Oracle Database

08/2019 - 07/2020 Adjunct Professor

Faculdade CDL, Brazil

• I taught Systems Analysis and Design for Systems Development to undergraduate students.

02/2013 - 02/2015 Adjunct Professor

Faculdade Ateneu, Brazil

• I taught Java programming, Fundamentals of Systems Analysis and Development, Information Technology, and Project Management to undergraduate students.

01/2013 - 03/2014 Project Manager

GREat - Group of Computer Networks, Software Engineering and Systems, Brazil

• I was involved and coordinated, following agile methodologies, the development of frameworks for building mobile applications (in partnership with SONY Mobile) integrated with social networks. We also evolved and implemented a recommendation engine, based on contextual information and social information.

GREat - Group of Computer Networks, Software Engineering and Systems, Brazil

• I worked as a developer at GREat in partnership with textbfSONY Mobile delivering applications, tools, and frameworks. We developed Android applications as proof of concept for innovations delivered to the partner.

01/2009 - 12/2010 **System Analyst**

GREat - Group of Computer Networks, Software Engineering and Systems, Brazil

• Worked as a developer at GREat in partnership with LG Eletronics delivering software customization for country adaptation (using C programming language) of LG Mobile phones. I also worked as a configuration manager, responsible for integrating source codes and delivering software releases.

EDUCATION -

2010 - 2012	Master's degree Master's degree in Computer Science - Software Engir	Federal University of Ceara neering
2019 - 2020	Graduate Degree Graduate Degree in Mobile Development	Estácio
2008 - 2010	Graduate Degree Graduate Degree in Data Base Management - Interurp	Estácio ted
2008 - 2010	Graduate Degree Graduate Degree, Information Technologies, emphasis	Federal University of Ceara in Development of WEB Software - Interurpted
2004 - 2007	Bachelor Degree Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Telematics	Federal Institute of Education, Science and Technology of Ceara

CERTIFICATION —

- · Oracle Certified Professional: Java SE 11 Developer
- · AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- · Scrum Fundamentals Certified Credential
- Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations 2020 Certified Associate (Expired in 2022)
- Certified Scrum Product Owner (Expired in 2022)

LANGUAGES -

- English C1 (Advanced) CLB9
- · Portuguese native